Welcome to this course focused on getting started with Model Contacts Protocol.
My name is Stephen Greider and I'll be guiding you through everything you need to know around MCP.
Let's first begin by understanding exactly what we'll cover in the coming videos.
We'll first get an overview on MCP and understand what problems it is intended to solve.
We'll then start to look at the basics of MCP architecture by covering the responsibilities of MCP clients and servers.
Then it is on to the three basic components of an MCP server.
First, we'll look at tools, which are intended to be consumed by language models.
After that, we'll study resources, which allow a server to share data with clients.
And finally, prompts, which will provide tuned directions to language models.
Now, there's a lot of content for us to get through, so there are a couple of requirements on your side.
First, you need to have some basic Python knowledge.
Second, we will be writing out some code, and this will require a local Python installation.
We will be managing our project with the uv-cli, and if you don't have it installed, I recommend grabbing it now.
Get a link to it on the screen.